

Blas Vicco

Computer Engineer

Argentina | Information Technology and Services

E-mail: <u>blasvicco@gmail.com</u>

Skype: blasvicco

LinkedIn: https://ar.linkedin.com/in/blasvicco

Summary:

I'm able to make difficult decisions and produce work without error in situations that are constantly stressful or time sensitive. Exceptionally well suited to positions that will demand continuous learning and imagining new and different ways of doing things. I love to encounter and solve exceptionally complicated problems being analytical, reflective, imaginative and creative.

Actively involved in different stages of IT projects contributing with code implementation and with tasks that implicate more responsibility like planning the projects, handling resources, task management, time effort estimation, requirement analysis and software architecture design.

I have other complementary experience planning and teaching courses for the informatics area of the "Honorable Cámara de Diputados de la Provincia de Santa Fe" about advanced Linux and Web development; also, for the "FICH-CIMNE" classroom of the "Universidad Nacional del Litoral" about C++ development and numerical process.

I worked with the application "SolidWork Simulation" and the FEM (Finite Element Methodology) to detect and analyze the resonant frequency effects in an industrial transformer and to make a structural study of an agricultural sprinkler.

I used C++ with numerical libraries to develop a simple problem type for the application "GID" (http://gid.cimne.upc.es/).

I had to use C++ to develop an ANN (Artificial Neuronal Network) for an intelligent IP filter, also to compete in the Alifecontest-microorganisms (http://alifecontest.wikidot.com/inicio).

My work profile: https://app.plum.io/profile/blasvicco

My personality type: https://www.16personalities.com/enfps-at-work

Experience:

Software Developer at **Avature** (https://www.avature.net/) January 2016 – November 2016 | Buenos Aires – Argentina

Developer Team Manager at **ContactPoint** now **Convirza** (https://www.convirza.com/) November 2011 – August 2015 | Utah – US (Remote)

Project Manager / Requirements Analyst at **Serfe** (http://www.serfe.com/) 2006 – 2011 | Santa Fe – Argentina

Projects:

- SmartContent (http://www.smartcontent.tk/):

This is a complete example of a Symfony project. At this point, users can use this WebApp in order to create Google Alerts and review the contents that SmartContent will automatically retrieve from the Google Alert emails.

SmartContent will connect to Gmail and read the emails from Google Alerts. It will capture the links and put them in a queue to be processed. SmartContent will read the links from the queue and will try to retrive the content. After that, it will classify and summarize them. Users will be able to list, filter and review all the content processed for the WebApp.

More details at (https://github.com/blasvicco/smartcontent)

- **HitApp.me** (http://www.hitapp.me/):

An Android app developed using Android SDK that allows users to share their location with special tags or categories. Users can find each other using these categories. The result list is sorted by proximity. Other options are available in the app like get directions, contact the selected user and even rate them.

The backend is an implementation of a REST API using:

- -. Phalcon PHP framework (https://phalconphp.com/en)
- -. PostgresSQL (http://www.postgresgl.org/)

- blood-donor-Angular-project (https://quiet-fjord-59665.herokuapp.com/):

This is a complete example of an Angular project.

Users can become blood donors just by completing a simple form and selecting their address in a map. The data in the form will be validated. An email to confirm the account will be sent after submitting the form. The email includes a link to edit the donor information and even delete it. The map that shows the donors will update automatically after a new donor is added or updated (broadcast) in the view range of the clients. The contact info of the donors will be hidden until the visitors click on it to avoid spam robots.

More details at (https://github.com/blasvicco/blood-donor-angular-project)

- Social-Media-Analytics (https://social-media-analytic.herokuapp.com):

This is a complete example of a BackboneJs and RequireJs project.

The web app will call a RestAPI to retrieve a large JSON that contains a collection of social media metadata. The data will be parsed as a list of items to be reviewed. The user can filter the items in the list. The user can also delete an item or select a bunch of them to set it as completed. User will be able to clear all the completed reviewed items.

More details at (https://github.com/blasvicco/Social-Media-Analytics)

Education:

Universidad Nacional del Litoral - Argentina COMPUTER ENGINEER 1999 – 2010

Universidad Nacional del Litoral - Argentina APPLIED COMPUTER ANALYST 2000 – 2004